STEFAN DEZARN | DATA ANALYST

stefandezarn.com +1 540 327 1226 | me@stefandezarn.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated, technically-minded problem solver with years of experience utilizing various methodologies for analysis that leads to intelligent decision making. Interested in identifying patterns in order to see the bigger picture and excited to learn more every day.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Python (Pandas, Matplotlib, SciKit-Learn, etc.)
- ✓ R (tidyverse, ggplot2, etc.)
- SQL (BigQuery, MSSQL, MySQL)
- Microsoft Excel

- ✓ Tableau
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Google Suite
- Source control

RELEVANT PROJECTS

All projects available for review at stefandezarn.com

Concrete Strength Correlation Analysis

Utilizing Python, I do the following:

- Import, inspect and clean the dataset
- Perform analysis of the correlations between independent variables and the target variable in preparation for using machine learning to predict strengths.

Sales and Business Analysis

Utilizing Azure Data Studio and the T-SQL syntax, I create a database from CSV files, ask business questions and use ad-hoc queries to answer them.

Cyclistic Bikeshare Analysis

Utilizing the R programming language, I do the following:

- Import, inspect, and clean the dataset in a Jupyter Notebook
- Perform analysis and provide vizualizations relevant to the business task

EDUCATION

Virginia Commonwealth University | 2007 - 2011

Bachelor of Science - Physics

- Presidential Scholarship Award
- Graduated Cum Laude

Google Data Analytics Career Certificate | 2022-23

Jovian Data Analysis with Python Certificate | 2023

WORK HISTORY

Kumar and Associates, Inc.

Geotechnical Engineering Lab/Field Technician | Aug 2015 - Present

- Performed materials testing and inspections for construction activities.
- Created and maintained databases of test/lab results.

Colorado Motor Parts, Inc.

Operations Manager | Jan 2014 - Aug 2015

 Utilized and maintained inventory database and delivery management system to ensure efficiency of operations.